<idea-plugin>
    <id>opencodedock</id>
    <name>OpenCode Dock</name>
    <version>1.3.4</version>
    <vendor>Przemyslaw Segrecki</vendor>

    <description><![CDATA[
        <p>OpenCode Dock brings OpenCode into a dedicated JetBrains tool window that follows the active IDE theme.</p>
        <h4>Features:</h4>
        <ul>
            <li>Installation, update, and authentication flows for the OpenCode runtime inside the plugin.</li>
            <li>Communication with OpenCode through ACP (Agent Client Protocol) in a GUI.</li>
            <li>Structured display of agent output, including tool use, thinking blocks, terminal commands, plans, file edits, and diffs.</li>
            <li>Review of files changed by an agent, with options to accept selected changes or revert them from the IDE.</li>
            <li>Audio notifications for important chat and agent events.</li>
            <li>Slash commands and @ mentions backed by JetBrains project file search.</li>
            <li>Code selections and file references can be added to chat from the editor and project view.</li>
            <li>Images can be pasted into chat and previewed inline.</li>
            <li>Live token quota and context usage are shown directly in the chat input while prompting, when available from OpenCode.</li>
            <li>Voice input for prompts (Windows only).</li>
            <li>Chats can be continued in the IDE terminal when CLI mode is a better fit.</li>
            <li>Chat history supports opening, renaming, deleting, and bulk deletion.</li>
            <li>Chats can be forked from any point.</li>
            <li>MCP server configuration for additional agent tools and external resources.</li>
            <li>Reusable prompts can be saved in the prompt library and inserted into chat when needed.</li>
            <li>System instructions can be managed and applied to agent sessions.</li>
            <li>Git commit messages can be generated from the current changes.</li>
        </ul>
        <h4>Requirements:</h4>
        <ul>
            <li>JetBrains IDE based on IntelliJ Platform 2025.1 or newer.</li>
            <li>OpenCode uses the JetBrains IDE terminal for some authentication and runtime flows.</li>
            <li>On macOS and Linux, installing the runtime requires curl and tar.</li>
        </ul>
    ]]></description>

    <change-notes><![CDATA[
        <ul>
            <li>OpenCode 1.16.2 compatibility: model selection now reads from ACP configOptions instead of legacy models field.</li>
            <li>New Effort dropdown for models that support reasoning levels (low/default/high).</li>
            <li>History loading is now asynchronous and non-blocking: cached data appears instantly while background sync runs.</li>
            <li>Fixed session loading for historical conversations broken by OpenCode 1.16.2 missing sessionId in session/load response.</li>
            <li>Fixed history item conversationId mismatch causing wrong tab activation.</li>
            <li>Updated plugin icons to OpenCode brand.</li>
        </ul>
    ]]></change-notes>

     <depends>com.intellij.modules.platform</depends>
     <extensions defaultExtensionNs="com.intellij">
<toolWindow id="OpenCode Dock" icon="/icons/opencode.svg" anchor="right"
                     factoryClass="opencodedock.OpenCodeDockToolWindowFactory"/>
     </extensions>

    <actions>
        <action id="OpenCodeDock.AddCodeReferenceToChatAction"
                class="opencodedock.AddCodeReferenceToChatAction"
                text="Add to Chat"
                description="Add the selected code range to the chat input"
                icon="/icons/opencode.svg">
            <add-to-group group-id="EditorPopupMenu" anchor="first"/>
        </action>
        <action id="OpenCodeDock.AddFileReferenceToChatAction"
                class="opencodedock.AddFileReferenceToChatAction"
                text="Add to Chat"
                description="Add the selected file reference to the chat"
                icon="/icons/opencode.svg">
            <add-to-group group-id="ProjectViewPopupMenu" anchor="first"/>
        </action>
        <action id="OpenCodeDock.GenerateGitCommitMessageAction"
                class="opencodedock.gitcommit.GenerateGitCommitMessageAction"
                text="Generate Commit Message"
                description="Generate a commit message with the configured AI agent"
                icon="/icons/opencode.svg">
            <add-to-group group-id="Vcs.MessageActionGroup" anchor="last"/>
        </action>
    </actions>
</idea-plugin>
